All right, guys. I wasn't planning on
recording. I just got home from work. I
have to make this video. I ended up
watching one of Ab and Preach's videos
on Amanda Seales. I love people that
make me think. Whenever the majority of
people feels a certain way, I always try
to look at the other side because a lot
of times I can't trust the majority. You
don't know who's choosing majority
because they actually chose it or just
because most people are choosing it. I
was listening to Ab and Preach talk
about Amanda Seales and they were
playing a clip of Amanda. It kind of
reminded me of an affirmation routine
someone would do in their bathroom
mirror. She was on it, too, like
>> I am a genius. I'm a gifted performer. I
am a gifted person. I am a creative
genius. I'm generous. I am giving. I am
kind. I'm funny. I'm delightful. These
are not things that I need to wait for
somebody to say about me. I know these
things about myself.
>> I think the part that was confusing me
is that I don't think there's enough
authenticity in this world. And a big
part of what Amanda was saying was I am
authentic. This is me. This is who I am.
When people can stand in their
authenticity, especially black women, I
love [clears throat] that. I think she's
half like me. I don't know for sure.
Sorry if I'm wrong. What I was observing
in myself when I was listening to part
of the clip and I was watching her say
with conviction, I am a genius. I am
gifted. All the [ __ ] I would say in my
bathroom mirror and just hope I could
believe 50% of it one day.
>> I am [ __ ] Scully and Mulder. I'm a
crusader. Like I'm the Green Beret.
>> I believed Amanda. I believe she
believed everything that she was
declaring with confidence. We should be
able to stand in our truth. That is also
something that I don't think enough
people do. I think people sort of drift
toward groups and they're not individual
enough. The conflict I was having was
that I agreed with what Amanda was
saying. Humans should 100% be able to
stand in their truth with confidence.
But as she's saying this, why am I
having that reaction that a lot of
people have with her?
>> The unfortunate part of that is that
it's not a reflection of me, it's a
reflection of them.
>> Right.
>> So I had to examine that. Am I having
this conflicting feeling because I am
small?
>> Why do you feel small? What's going on
with you?
>> Because I feel threatened by Amanda.
>> Who made you feel that way? That's not
fair to you. Come on, rise up. It's in
you.
>> And so I had to go through it. So I was
like, okay, if she's a genius, she could
be way smarter than me. But also, would
it intimidate me? I don't think so
because if I had, let's say, the
opportunity to hang out with Neil
deGrasse Tyson for a day, I would be
over the moon. I might feel stupid all
day, but I would be excited. Would it be
her beauty? She absolutely absolutely is
beautiful.
>> I think some people don't like me
because I'm very light-skinned.
>> It's great to be not only beautiful on
the outside, like Amanda, but also a
genius and smart and a scholar of She
said she was a scholar of something.
>> I'm a scholar of race.
>> Well-read.
>> I'm a scholar. I'm an academic of race.
>> On top of that, having this incredible
amount of confidence.
>> I see the world through a particular
lens because I am skilled at doing so.
>> I don't think we're capable of loving
others unless we love ourselves.
>> It's cuz I'm lovable and people like me
and I'm delightful.
>> Not really sure how true that is, but
but I definitely know the better I feel
about myself, the better I can feel
about others and the more I want to do
for others. But I do it for a living. So
it's like, why am I having this
conflicting feeling? Why do I feel like
I wouldn't want to go to the zoo with
her or something? I don't know.
>> I am delightful.
>> And although I'm an introvert, I love
being with outgoing people as long as
they're okay with me being me, which a
lot of times is just, you know, walking
behind you staring at the tree over
there. It's more about you being
yourself and me being able to be me. If
she had suggested that it was when
strong women or strong, you know, humans
are around small humans, it will
threaten the small humans.
>> I don't know how being unabashedly smart
has become such a villainous thing.
Literally people think that me being a
critical thinker is me being extra. Me
being too much. But there were a lot of
people who used to say things like that
about, you know, Stokely Carmichael,
about Huey P, about Martin Luther King.
Like, "Oh, THEY'RE STIRRING UP TROUBLE."
>> WOW.
>> SHE'S achieved an incredible amount of
accomplishments. And I was like, I don't
I don't think it's any of those. So,
what is it? What's bothering me?
>> I have become the patron saint for
difficult women.
>> Her observation of it being people are
small, people are intimidated, people
feel threatened.
>> What is it about me that makes you feel
small?
>> Well, you're just difficult.
>> I'm an advocate for authenticity, for
honesty, for self-love, which she has a
lot of, beauty, which she also has a lot
of. I agree with her words, but I don't
want to go to lunch with her.
>> What did you do?
>> I ARRIVED.
>> [laughter]
>> SHE'S APPARENTLY blacklisted and people
don't like her, but technically what
she's declaring, I'm all about that. So,
what conflict am I having with her?
>> Because you have someone who is an
expert sitting in front of you. Just
consider versus be combative because
there may be an opportunity here to see
something differently [clears throat]
because you have someone with you who is
not just experiencing race, but is also
examining. There's a different
intellectualism about that. You know
what I mean?
>> I feel like if
with a head like mine, I should have
Amanda's level of knowledge. But
>> If that's a source ire for you, like I'm
I'm like mad.
>> I could be full of horse [ __ ] right now,
to be honest, but I think there are
different components to intelligence.
You could have a 160 IQ and also litter.
And to me, that's part of intelligence,
like don't be dumb, throw your trash
away. A type of intelligence or a
component of intelligence that doesn't
really get talked about as much is
relational awareness. I'm not a
scientist or a psychologist, but
I've always been intrigued with I don't
know why the [ __ ] I'm even talking about
this. Basically, the the ability to
understand what another human being is
experiencing while you're communicating
with them. Relational awareness, I think
it's tricky. This is what was getting me
caught up was authenticity asks, am I
expressing myself honestly? She's being
authentic, but I think relational
awareness asks, what is my environment
experiencing
while I am expressing myself?
>> What do you think you did to that young
lady for her to feel that way towards
you?
>> I've no idea.
>> Although I wholeheartedly agree with
being authentic, I still think the
component of being aware of your
surroundings and and how you're
affecting that can still be adjusted
without you abandoning your
authenticity. So, for instance, me being
introverted and although I may not want
to smile and say hello, I'll do it
because I have relational awareness.
>> You know you know what? Yeah, you know
what? Fine. Yeah. I owe you money. Yeah.
>> I'm a nurse. Being in a hospital, there
are times that I pray with families if
they ask me to. That's low-key noble.
I'm an atheist and I don't believe in
what they believe. My relational
awareness says, what is my goal? Is my
goal to debate whatever belief my
patient and their family has?
>> Aren't we supposed to be God's children?
>> Yeah.
>> Or is the goal to connect or to provide
comfort?
>> Don't forget spiritually,
cuz it's about what's under the skin.
>> What are we trying to achieve in that
moment? She mentioned a lot that people
get on her for correcting others.
>> Amanda is correcting me.
>> My thought is, if I hear someone
pronounce a word wrong, what tells me
whether I should correct them or not?
>> So, I was that student.
>> For instance, if if I'm talking to
someone who's about to go on a TED stage
and give a speech and I noticed a word
they pronounced was wrong, it would be
necessary for me to say, "Hey, you're
saying tomato, but it's actually
tomato." My goal would be to correct
that because I want this person to give
a great speech. But, if it's in a
setting where my goal is to connect with
the person rather than correct a word
that is going to puncture the momentum
of the conversation or the momentum of
the connection, it's a level of
intelligence that would say, "This is
not the environment to correct another
person." Same with religion. When I'm
with friends that believe in God, what
is my goal? Is my goal to argue my views
on atheism or is my goal to connect? In
certain environments, it very well could
be to argue my my points. I'm going to
use a subject that I know well, okay?
I hope I'm in focus, guys. I'm sorry if
I'm not. I would be closer to the
camera, but my forehead is so big that
when I get closer, it just is like a
solar eclipse.
>> And it's okay.
>> Most of us know what B12 is, right? B12
is incredibly valuable. Let's say B12 is
Amanda's knowledge. She has a ton of
B12. Amanda wants to spread that
knowledge and share that with others.
The thing with B12 is that we could have
a ton of B12 in our system, but B12 is
something that can't be absorbed without
something called intrinsic factor. It's
a protein in our stomach. We're going to
say this is intrinsic factor cuz this
kind of looks like a part of an
intestine, so we'll say this is
intrinsic factor. We cannot absorb B12
without intrinsic factor. Someone could
say something to me and the tone
determines whether I receive it or not,
whether a wall goes up and I don't
really hear them because I I feel my
identity was threatened before I had an
opportunity to actually receive the
information.
>> The tone that I speak in doesn't make
them feel a certain way.
>> Cuz you mean you speaking in a mean
tone.
>> [snorts]
>> Here's Amanda's knowledge. Amanda's
knowledge is walking along
>> That is part of my autism.
>> And she wants to share this knowledge,
right? With this person right here.
Here's a person. Intrinsic factor in our
belly is Amanda's relational awareness.
>> I see [ __ ]
>> The gap is the delivery.
>> And it's going to stink. That's how you
convey your messages. When it lands in
my hand, it's going to be [ __ ]
>> I think where people get stuck is how
they transfer that information.
>> I do not need to change my energy.
>> See what I mean? You're not considerate.
>> Some people need more intrinsic factor.
>> I don't.
>> But damn, I mean I can't take you
nowhere.
>> No matter how much B12 we have, we
cannot absorb it without relational
awareness.
>> There's probably about 5% of those
situations where like yeah, oh you want
an apology.
>> This was really an exploration of
myself, not Amanda, but it gave me
something to think about because I
agreed with what she was saying. It's
how you deliver it and understanding
human beings and how we receive things,
I think it's probably just as important
as the information you're trying to
share.
>> I very rarely include my feelings.
>> Me smiling and saying hello or laughing
at a joke that I didn't really think it
was that funny because I want to have a
person keep their dignity. As an
atheist, pray with a Muslim family or a
LDS family at their dying loved one's
bedside, I will absolutely pray with
them. I think it's all about the goal,
take care of my patients and provide
support. But if something needs to be
spoken for and and there is an underdog
that needs to be protected, I can also
do that. But it's knowing when.
>> I went and got my masters because I know
that we live in a world that loves to
try and find ways to undermine black
people's minds.
>> You trying to
>> [snorts]
>> Are you trying to put me in these
shackles?
>> Yeah.
>> Another part of intelligence is knowing
where your knowledge stops and where
you're interpreting other people's
motives.
>> I just don't ever feel comfortable with
people forming opinions not based on
truth.
I think some people don't like me
because [clears throat] I may reflect
something that they desire. I think some
people don't like me because I'm a woman
with a very strong point of view and an
opinion. You don't like me because I can
talk proper or something. I think some
people don't like me for the reasons
that they don't like themselves.
>> To be able to declare that other people
are threatened or intimidated.
>> Well, no, I'm just being honest.
>> That would take a little more humility
to understand that it it's not
knowledge. That that part is not your
knowledge. That's your interpretation.
>> There is the truth, there is my truth,
and a lot of times maybe it's the same.
>> Okay. Uh
>> Part of intelligence is being able to
see the boundary between knowledge and
your interpretation of other people. Um
Yeah. So, thank you for listening to my
thoughts on Amanda. This one was tough
cuz there's a lot she said that that I
do agree with. So, I wanted to kind of
examine why I was having that
conflicting feeling cuz I hate being on
the side of the majority, but I but I
unfortunately was with with this one.
So,
>> It took us a little bit, but you here.
>> I hope you guys have a good night.
Thanks for letting me talk to you, and
thanks for watching.
>> Carry on.
>> [laughter]
>> It took you a long time.
>> Oh my god.
>> Eight years.